MICHAEL CONDON

michaelcondon@outlook.com https://michaelcondon.me

Overview

I am Sydney based IT professional; I have extensive experience in client-facing (in person) technical support and sales. I have worked for Microsoft Australia for 7 years and I am intimately familiar with Microsoft technologies. I am seeking employment to further my technical skills and enter a role where I can both learn and teach new technologies and methodologies.

Skills & Abilities

My years of experience in retail and customer-facing support have given me refined soft-skills, in particular my ability to communicate technical details to non-technical clients is noteworthy. My other valuable skills include:

- Strong verbal and written skills
- Confident public speaker
- Exemplary client-facing support (Helpdesk)
- Great decision making and leadership skills
- Eager to learn and to teach
- Comfortable in mentor roles
- Intermediate .NET development skills (C# & PowerShell)
- Intermediate Front & Back End web development skills
- Basic System Administration skills in both Linux & Windows
- Fiercely passionate about Information Security and Security Policy

Experience

2012-2017 Microsoft Brand Ambassador

Microsoft Australia/CPM Australia

The primary role of a Microsoft Brand Ambassador is to assist in retail sales, planning and executing POS merchandising, and providing face to face support for Microsoft customers. My other notable responsibilities were:

- Staff training, organizing and executing training seminars
- Orientation and training for new hires
- Managing relationships with key stakeholders at a store level
- Technical support for Microsoft customers
- Collecting and reporting store level sales data and trends
- Acting as an ambassador at corporate events for Microsoft partners across Surface, Office, and Windows businesses

2017-Current Services Advisor

Microsoft Australia

A Services Advisor's role is to provide customer-facing support for Microsoft's consumer and commercial products. Primarily providing support to individual consumers and small-medium business owners, a Services Advisor's role can be split into two primary responsibilities:

Front of House (Customer facing):

- Engaging with clients and resolving technical issues
- Troubleshooting hardware and software problems
- Managing a ticket system using Dynamics 365
- Providing education to SMB customers on Microsoft's commercial offerings
- Setting up and deploying Office 365 and cloud solutions

Back of House (Technical):

- Manage 10-20 client devices checked in for repair
- Maintain compliance with customer data and PII
- Develop tools to troubleshoot and repair specific Windows issues and automate workflow
- Create and Maintain relevant on-boarding content for new hires
- Maintain professional communication with clients on the status of their devices and services.

Education

2013-2014 Certificate IV Programming

NSW TAFE

- Learned basic to intermediate programming concepts using Java and C#, as well as web development and database skills.
- Studied Project management techniques with a focus on agile methodologies

2014-2014 Diploma of Software Development

NSW TAFE. Graduated with Distinction

- Completed a major project to be delivered to a real-life business client, worked in a team of three to develop an online system utilizing Microsoft .NET technologies
- Learned advanced programming techniques using C# and frameworks such as MVC.
- Created system documentation using the UML design language.
- Developed and implemented an agile scrum-like development methodology used during our major project.
- Liaised with clients to find project requirements and rationalize them into system functionality
- Studied and implemented Verification and Validation, writing test cases and observing industry V&V practices.